

# Jorge Oliver López Fierro

WEB Developer

### About me

I am a software developer with a focus on development front-end in web systems, despite my age I have already had the opportunity to develop systems that have been important for the development of my knowledge and work experience. I have knowledge in web design and layout, I also have the necessary experience to support the back-end development of a web system without problems.

## Education, courses and certificates



### **Cross-platform Software Development**

Universidad Tecnológica de Emiliano Zapata September 2018- August 2020



### Software development and management Engineering

Universidad Tecnológica de Emiliano Zapata August 2020- January 2021 (Paused) 8°



### **Scrum Fundamentals**

SCRUM Study January 2022



### Introduction to **Artificial Intelligence**

ORACLE Oracle Academy October 2020

### **Personal Information**

### **Email**

≥ oliverde10021@gmail.com

### Cellphone

**1** +52 (777) 225-0917

### Personal

- **9** June, 3, 1998
- **9** 23 years

### Ubicación

• Cuernavaca. Morelos

### Languages

**English** 

Intermediate level

**Spanish** Native

## **Work Experience**



### Hospital de Alta Especialidad "Centenario de la Revolución Mexicana"

Full Stack developer may 2020 - november 2020 (7 months)

- •Realization of requirements survey and implementation together every third day to brainstorm and gather information
- Make the necessary ERD diagrams and use cases.
- Layout web page with Figma interactively to show the required functionalities to the client before coding the system.
- Support the development of the ERD diagram and after database development

MySQL using MySQL Workbench.

- Develop web platform using HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, Responsive Design, JQuery and under the scrum methodology.
- · Support back-end development through language of PHP programming and its Symfony framework, developed the functionalities necessary for the web system.

### **Technologies used**

MySQL

**SCRUM** 

**JQuery** 

HTML5

CSS

Boostrap

**JavaScript** 

PHP

Responsive

Symfony



### **Social Conecta**

SOCIAL Web Designer

January 2021 - June 2021 (6 Months)

- Create visual web designs through packaging Adobe (Photoshop and Illustrator).
- Interactive web layout with Figma.

### **Technologies used**

Asana

Adobe

Wordpress

**Figma** 

# **Jorges Lubricantes**

### Freelance front end developer june 2021 - july 2021 (1 month)

### **Technologies used**

- Web page redesign.
- Show new web design with Figma.
- Create backup copies of the web page on the contracted server.
- Set up a new web page on the server.
- · Code new web page from the new design with HTML5, CSS, Responsive Design.

Apache	Wordpress	JQuery
HTML5	CSS	Boostrap
JavaScript	Responsive	

## Linnegocios

Linnegocios Full stack developer

july 2021 - october 2021

(4 months)

### **Technologies used**

- Support the service payment systems support section.
- Support the implementation of new functionalities to the system, both web and Android app.
- Update obsolete designs of the WEB platform with HTML5, GSP, Bootstrap, SASS, Responsive Design.
- · Support in solving errors found and giving maintenance weekly to the system.
- Support in backend through Groovy programming language. in conjunction with the Grails framework.
- Weekly will gather needs under the SCRUM methodology.

GSP	SASS	JQuery
HTML5	css	Android Studio
JavaScript	Responsive	Groovy
Grails	SCRUM	

### Indra BBVA

Front end developer

BBV | november 2021 - may 2022

(7 months)

### **Technologies used**

Creation of components for the mobile application of the BBVA bank.

· Solution and correction of errors and continuous improvement through constant feedback.

• Continuous training on its framework (Cells and Lit Element) based on web components.

- Use of the best front end development rules through its documentation.
- The project was based on an agile SCRUM methodology.

### CELLS LitElement JQuery WEB Android CSS Components Studio Responsive **JavaScript** Jira BBVA SCRUM Documents



### **GFT BBVA**

Front end developer

august 2022 - january 2023

(6 months)

- Creation of components for the mobile application of the BBVA bank.
- Solution and correction of errors and continuous improvement through constant feedback.
- Continuous training on its framework (Cells and Lit Element) based on web components.
- Use of the best front end development rules through its documentation.
- The project was based on an agile SCRUM methodology.

### **Technologies used**

**Documents** 



# Technologies and abilities

### programming Design Herramientas **Database** languages **Javascript** Adobe Adobe ReactJS mongoDB, MongoDB Figma React Native JavaScript Python



